# Ryan Grimes

CV



+447890382345



16 Hamilton Court, Harbour Views, Gibraltar



ryanpaulgrimes@gmail.com



/in/ryanpgrimes



github.com/RPGrimes



rpgrimes.vercel.app

## **Coding Experience**

Languages

- ✓ Javascript
- ✓ Ruby
- ✓ Experience using SQL

Frameworks

- ✓ React JS
- ✓ Node JS
- ✓ Express JS
- ✓ Sinatra
- ✓ Rails

Hosting

- ✓ Heroku
- ✓ Vercel

**Testing** 

- ✓ Jest
- ✓ RSpec
- ✓ Capybara

Tools & Other

- ✓ Command Line
- ✓ GitHub
- ✓ HTML
- ✓ CSS
- ✓ SCSS✓ VScode
- ✓ RESTful API
- ✓ Pair programming

#### Education

Full Stack Software Engineering Makers Academy October 2021 to January 2022

**MSc Engineering Geology**, University of Portsmouth - Distinction September 2015 to August 2016

**BSc Geology**, Royal Holloway University of London - Upper Second Class Honours (2.1) September 2012 to July 2015

### **Profile**

A determined and driven full-stack developer with a strong foundation in software development and programming principles.

Well versed in following Agile workflow and keeping to a clean and precise Test Driven Development process.

An excellent team-member with previous experience working to strict client specifications and meeting deadlines as required.

## **Featured Projects**

HEYDAY - https://github.com/RPGrimes/heyday

This application helps to organize a meetup of friends by choosing a date for them based on the whole group's availability and preferences, all while maintaining individuals' privacy and not storing any user data.

Tech stack:

- React JS
- Express JS
- SCSS
- Hosted using Vercel (frontend) and Heroku (backend)
- Github

ACEBOOK - https://github.com/RPGrimes/acebook

A social media site inspired by Facebook. Users are able to post both messages and images to a newsfeed, in addition to be able to like and comment on individual posts.

#### Tech stack:

- Ruby on Rails
- PostgreSQL
- Bootstrap CSS
- Github

## **Employment History**

CARD GEOTECHNICS LIMITED (CGL)

Senior Engineer - June 2019 to August 2021 Engineer - September 2016 to June 2019

- Management and supervision of projects throughout London and southern England
- Client liason for a number of major clients and responsible for company relationship building with a range of clients from a range of different disciplines
- Formal mentor for both graduate and junior engineers
- Reviewing and producing reports for clients consistently on time and on-budget
- Working between several teams (both internal and external to CGL) in a collaborative manner throughout the course of a project lifetime.